[audio logo]
[bird calling]
[gentle music]
[crow calling]
♪ ♪
[wind blowing]
[snorting]
[wolf howling]
[panting]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[growling]
[pig squealing]
[squealing]
[barking, snarling]
[gunshot]
[wind howling]
[grunts]
[groans]
[gentle music]
♪ ♪
You weren't afraid,
were you, Dix?
♪ ♪
Come on.
I want to go see Dad.
♪ ♪
Outpost log entry 516, first
week of the new year, '65.
The different set
of handwriting here at the end,
different because this is
my first and last entry
into this logbook.
Major General Edward James
Horn, retired US Army officer
and Pinkerton, is deceased,
four weeks, pneumonia,
buried by his daughter
and only living kin,
Adeline Elizabeth Horn.
The ground was almost
too frozen to dig into.
[distant laughter]
man: Watch him ride right by.
You better circle back.
Dig, dig.
[squealing]
Gus.
You little survivor.
man: Today, circle back.
♪ ♪
Adeline: The outpost will be
abandoned within a day or two
at most, as conditions
have become too harsh.
I've sent letters to Camp Watson
and to the Pinkerton offices
in Chicago requesting
a replacement,
but I've received no word back.
My fear that I have been
forgotten by the world
is overwhelmed
by a deeper fear...
that I was never known at all.
In keeping with my
father's intent,
all supplies will be kept
here, ready and available
for any Union soldier in need.
I'm also leaving this
logbook behind as a marker
that we were here.
Adeline Elizabeth Horn.
♪ ♪
I don't know how
I'll earn my way,
and I know that I am letting
my father down by leaving.
I am not the caretaker he was.
I saw a man today,
a soul lost to the wilderness,
and I did not call out
to help him.
♪ ♪
[wind blowing]
[distant knocking]
[clatter]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[shuffling, rattling]
man: Put that light out!
I said, put that thing out,
unless'n you want to get us
both killed.
Where are you keeping
your daddy's garments?
Come on, girlie.
I know you ain't here
by your lonesome.
Come on, out with it.
Bedroom dresser.
Wait now.
How old?
First thing's gon' be first.
Come over here.
Sit down.
We don't have any money.
Well, that's what
they call an assumption.
Adeline: But we do have plenty
of food and water, medicine.
You don't need a gun.
My father has had
Army medical training
and should be returning from
his midnight walk presently.
As for me, I know a great deal
about nursing and dressing.
I bandaged myself today.
Bah, foolishness.
Midnight walk.
Get over here and
bring that chair.
You said you weren't
gonna do nothing to me.
Darn right.
Oh, you'll be safe.
[laughs]
I'm a bunny rabbit.
You've got no cause to
tie me up and bully me.
I've told you.
I saw this camp 100
yards out, like an oasis
right there in the
middle of wild nowhere.
Open.
[groaning]
[grunts]
[groans]
Nothing.
Oh, figures.
Oh, my.
Oh, now this is warmth.
Tell you what.
Look at old Perry.
[laughs]
That's my father's coat.
Oh, he won't mind none.
Gon' be cold.
He's going to track you down
after I tell him
what you did to me,
though I was
unarmed and offered assistance.
Perry: Well, you go
right ahead, girlie.
It ain't your daddy
I'm 'fraid of.
Barlow.
Yeah.
Go west, Perry.
Watch him ride right by.
You better circle back.
Dig, dig.
So long, girlie.
Wait, you can't
leave me like this.
Perry: Your daddy will
untie you upon his return.
Adeline: I lied.
No one's coming to find me.
It's just me here.
I don't mind you taking
the clothes or the bread
or the liquor,
but you can't leave me
like this,
tied to a chair,
left to die like a fool.
Just you?
Adeline: Yes, sir.
I won't cause you no trouble.
You have my word.
[donkey braying]
Perry: Listen, girlie,
he's on his way now.
He don't sleep,
so I don't either.
Wish I could wish you nice,
but the rain coming my way
won't fall on you none.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
[coin clatters, rolls]
Watch him ride right by.
Circle back.
Dig, dig.
man: Colonel, you are faced
with an inevitability.
[scream, gunshot]
[gunshot]
[agonizing screams]
You will die on this mountain.
[grunting]
I've ordered my men to toss
your regiment into the river,
and your blood will
saturate these woods.
It was a cowardly
surprise attack.
man: I'm looking for a
man, goes by the name
of Burial Perry Parker.
I don't know this man, Parker.
man: That is not what
I was hoping to hear.
[stifled yell]
[gentle music]
♪ ♪
Adeline: What do
you think, Dixie?
♪ ♪
[crow calling]
I fear I am dead in this place
without this gold, so I took it.
Do not judge me.
You raised me well enough, but
you have not been where I am.
I'll say goodbye
to you both, and I
will start my journey
southwest to the settlers road
and then on to Astoria.
I cannot bring you with me.
But I love you, and I will
return for your portraits
one day when I am no longer
fearful of being hunted.
♪ For mine eyes
have seen the glory ♪
♪ of the coming of the Lord ♪
♪ He's trampling out the
vintage where the grapes ♪
♪ of wrath are stored ♪
♪ His truth is marching on ♪
♪ Mine eyes
Have seen the glory ♪
♪ of the coming of the Lord ♪
[distant gunshots]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
Come on.
We both have to
do our fair share.
[flies buzzing]
Shot to pieces.
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
Oh, my goodness.
You're alive.
But you won't be for
much longer out here.
[Dixie neighs]
♪ ♪
[crows calling]
It don't look deserted.
Sure ain't.
Edward Horn.
[distant chatter]
[laughter]
Adeline: They are Union.
We're safe.
Is this woman in
your party, soldier?
I'll be damned.
Colonel!
You are the
caretaker's daughter?
Yes, sir.
Ada.
We have been anticipating you.
Colonel John Good, Cavalry
Company G, Camp Watson.
Camp Watson?
Oh, thank God for you, Colonel.
You received my letters.
John: Do not let my
lieutenant here scare you.
I'm certain he's the first
full-blooded red paint
you've seen.
But he's a man for the
Union, same as you or I.
I saw the Union blue, sir.
Your logbook informs me
that your warden has passed.
It's been four weeks.
My condolences.
Your hand is injured.
I had a misfire.
My, you were shooting?
Yes, sir.
Who was the lucky target?
Wolves.
Soldier: Dry clothes, miss?
Plenty.
Soldier: Bring some socks and
all the blankets you've got.
John: Miss Horn, you were
equipped with a Franklin.
Yes, sir.
I'd appreciate some coffee.
It's been a month
since I had a cup.
I'll brew some.
Thank you.
[intriguing music]
♪ ♪
Miss Horn, where's my coffee?
Oh, brewing, Colonel.
[chuckles]
[horse neighs]
[grunts]
Will she be OK, Colonel?
She'll be fine.
I'm sure you've noticed we've
taken your Hawken rifle.
I apologize, but it's
a safety precaution.
You understand?
It's broken, so no matter.
I'll have Sergeant Baker
see if he can't repair it.
Colonel.
Miss Horn, we have what you
might call a delicate situation
on our hands.
I have a prisoner under my
guard that needs dealing with.
Red!
Red, look at me go!
Whoo!
I'm flying!
John: He's a dangerous man.
[groaning]
John: A thief.
Of course, you would not have
to be bothered by any of this,
except that it's over
four days' hard travel
down this mountain
to Camp Watson.
If this man is a
thief, Colonel, then he
should be dealt with
rightly by the court of law.
In times of peace and
civility, you would be right,
Miss Horn.
But these are
extraordinary times.
Colonel!
Come, then.
Join us.
Girlie!
Oh, thank Jesus.
Will you tell Fiddler
that I had nothing on me?
Nothing on me at all!
Tell him!
[choking]
John: Ada, this here
is Private CE Caldwell.
Miss Horn was kind
enough to return Miss
Emily to us safe and sound.
Comin' in.
Pleasure.
And this here
is Sergeant Baker.
You can call me Red.
Pleased to meet you both.
Perry: Well, girlie,
now that you've
met everyone all
cordial and mannerly,
will you please tell these
gentlemen I had nothing on me?
She heard you, Perry.
Please do not
interrupt me again.
Have you seen this man before?
Yes, sir.
He was in the cabin
two nights ago.
I-- I was just looking
for food and spirits.
I swear, Fiddler.
[coughing]
He's not lying, Colonel.
He didn't have nothing on him.
Nothing that I saw.
He was just in need of
bread and some whiskey.
And he stole nothing from you?
Perry: No, sir.
No, sir.
No.
The Chesterfield he's
wearing is my father's, and I'd
like it back.
Yeah.
Perry: No, no, no, no, no, no.
The man presently hanging
off your barn rafter
is Burial Perry Parker.
I know him well, and
I'm not fond of him.
He's a grave robber and a thief.
He has something
that belongs to me.
But he wouldn't have
the item on him.
It would be buried
in these woods.
[tense music]
Adeline: Colonel--
[gunshot]
[groaning, gasping]
Thank you, Sergeant.
Saddle up the horses.
We'll see where he takes us.
[groans]
I'm sorry that you had
to see that, Miss Horn.
I hope you'll forgive
us the intrusion.
Looks like we'll
be here overnight.
But don't you worry.
My men are happy to chew on
hardtack in the barn here,
so we'll be of no bother.
No.
I'll have supper ready for you
and your men
in the cabin shortly.
Why, thank you, Miss Horn.
It's Ada.
Ada.
[chuckles]
[moody music]
♪ ♪
[groaning]
[grunts, groans]
John: Untie him.
[groaning]
Dig.
♪ ♪
[pig squealing]
[gunshot]
Perry.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[grunting]
That sumbitch.
Come to give us a hand, kid?
Ground's frozen solid.
Winter around here
ain't a good time
for a man to meet his end.
You end up with no
place to put him.
[chuckles]
The, uh, colonel
know you're here?
That man has my father's
coat and his Wellington boots.
soldier: First time
seeing one, kid?
♪ ♪
No.
Hey, girl!
Ain't proper to bury a man
in no footwear whatsoever!
Man's gotta have the things
he needs going across.
I'm not the one
decided to shoot him.
♪ ♪
Here.
Your turn.
[gentle music]
[chimes, twinkling]
♪ ♪
[door creaks]
Emily, go and introduce
yourself to Miss Horn,
and bring that salt pork
to the supper table.
I can take these here plates.
Here.
I'm glad to see
you're up and about.
You'll let me know
if you need anything.
We're a fully stocked outpost.
John: While it's steaming!
[laughter]
You brought me here?
It was luck and clumsiness.
Well, I don't figure
I owe you nothing,
if that's what you think.
Red: Can't say I ever let
a whore eat before me.
Whore is further up the
food chain than scoundrel.
[laughter]
You've got a mouth on you.
I thank you, Ada.
Thanks, kid.
John: Since you've
been kind enough
to take us into your home,
I thought you might do
us the honor of saying grace.
Grace?
A blessing for the food.
I'm afraid I don't
know it, Colonel.
You don't need
anything prepared, Ada.
But if you were feeling shy--
[men chuckling]
I'm not shy.
I know the prayer my
father used to say.
Well, let's hear it, then.
Give us the
strength, good Lord,
to set the world at naught,
so that we may make a cry
unto Thee
in this hour
of our country's need.
Deal with us not by our
sins or our misdeeds,
but reach forth with Your
right hand and be our defense.
Have pity on our
brothers in arms
who are against the
authority of the land,
and allow them to see
the error of their ways.
Last, allow us to bear the
weight of the grief of those
we have known and loved.
And for those we do not know who
have passed on into the unknown,
we will remember always in
our silence and in our dreams.
Amen.
all: Amen.
Well, God damn.
I need a drink after that one.
[laughter]
We've got a full-blooded
Union loyalist, Colonel.
Drink up, kid.
Looks like we came
to the right place.
[laughter]
I don't pretend to know
more about the war than I do.
We are remote.
Though, a fur trader did
come through here on his way
to the Columbia River.
He had a February 5,
1862 New York Tribune.
He let me read it
through before he left.
What'd you gather from it?
Well, for one, the Yankee
paper's full of advertisements.
And I'd very much like to
see a live hippopotamus
from the Barnum Museum, and the
Commodore Nutt, who apparently
is the world's smallest man.
Him and the hippopotamuses
I'd like to see.
[laughter]
Though if what I saw today is
even a splinter of the war,
then I'm grateful to
not have taken part.
My punishment was too severe?
No, of course not.
Forgive me.
This is the most
I've spoken in weeks.
Your-- your daddy is passed?
He is dead.
Poor Daddy brought you up
on this godforsaken mountain
for what, swine husbandry?
I mean, God damn it, that
don't make one lick of sense.
Every man follows
his own path.
I mean, yeah, but her dad do
sound like a bit of a loon-o,
don't he?
Rob, that whiskey's gone
and soiled your etiquette.
My father was an operative
under Allan Pinkerton, sir.
That plaque in there, he
received upon his retirement
for a commendation
of excellence.
Not long after, we boarded the
SS Antelope at the Pacific wharf
in San Francisco, though
I remember none of it.
I was too young.
Caught sight of some gray
wolves out there, runt.
A few more than
I'd like to count.
Looks like they'll be knocking
on your door soon, missy.
Charlie: Gotta move them hogs.
That sow's got pneumonia.
She's going to pass soon.
I'm leaving here anyhow.
I'm going to California.
The gold rush is dead, Ada.
I'm surprised the news
ain't traveled to you.
It's been quite some time.
I'm not interested in gold.
Everyone is
interested in gold, Ada.
No, sir.
My mother is from San Francisco.
I figured I have some
family down that way.
Charlie: She's looking
to travel, Colonel.
See a hippopotamus or two.
Two would be something.
[laughter]
I don't reckon I'd like to be
stuck out here by my lonesome
neither.
No, sir.
John: We will be out
of your way soon.
We have business in these woods.
It should be
settled by tomorrow.
Even faster with your
help, if you don't
mind joining our expedition.
You know these woods
better than anyone.
Isn't that right?
Yes, sir.
John: As soon as our
business is finished,
we will leave you in peace.
[harmonica playing]
♪ ♪
[groans]
It was foolish to kill him.
Perry was a born liar.
Lied right till his last breath.
He was never going
to give up that gold.
What if he wasn't lying?
That the gold he stole
from me was stolen from him?
Burial could have told
her to move it for a cut.
Then where is it, Charlie?
You went over this
outpost same as me.
I seen no place it's
been buried or hung.
It ain't up in no God damn tree.
Yee-ha!
[gunshot]
[muffled gunshots, yelling]
[pigs squealing]
Yee-ha!
Woo!
[muffled gunshots]
[tense music]
[gunshots, yelling]
♪ ♪
[urine splattering]
[man grunting]
[whistling]
That's it.
[grunts]
Ada: Is your private not riding
with us this morning, Colonel?
He is sleeping off a headache.
Well, I've medicine
for that, Colonel.
[chuckles] I bet you do, Ada.
[unsettling music]
♪ ♪
How much do you
know about tracking?
I know the difference
between wolf and rabbit tracks.
[chuckles] I figured, since
your daddy was Pinkerton.
My lessons were cut short.
You said you'd
been fishing when
you returned to the outpost.
Ada: Tried to.
I camped on the way
to my favorite spot,
a bend in the river,
where the steelhead
get caught in a whirlpool.
I found Ms. Emily before
I could sink my line.
And you heard nothing
of our firefight?
Ada: I heard your
melee from a distance,
though, I was too scared
to move on in the morning.
John: But you did continue.
Hunger beats fear.
[horse huffs]
Keep your eyes to the ground.
Fresh tracks will show wet.
And the ground's been turned up.
Best thing we can
do is to start where
we found him, go from there.
You'll show me this
bend in the river.
Ada: Yes, sir.
[pensive music]
♪ ♪
Is that Father
and Mother Horn?
Ada: My father took great care
of making my mother's cross.
The cross I made for
him does not compare.
[chuckles] No, it does not.
We will make sure to
visit them properly
before we leave,
pay our respects.
♪ ♪
[reflective music]
[chimes twinkling]
♪ ♪
[distant laughter]
[unsettling music]
[footsteps]
[wood creaking]
Calvin: Still feeling
low, Ms. Emily?
You mean from you
leaving me to drown?
Calvin: I was
supposed to shoot you.
It was Mr. Fiddler's orders.
But you didn't.
Calvin: No, I shot your mare
instead, gave you a chance.
Mr. Perry showing up
gave you good cover,
but you weren't
supposed to reappear.
Is that what
you're here for now?
No.
Fiddler done changed his mind.
But I think I'll still give
you that punishment, though.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
[water splashing]
[horse neighs]
Red: Whoa.
[chuckles]
She was here.
Ada: Once your officer is
through checking my story,
there's a lookout point
not far from here.
I must show you.
It really is something.
Charlie: You just gonna keep
letting her mouth off like that?
John: What would you have me do?
I believe this young
lady has taken over
as leader of this expedition.
[laughter]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
This map is full of
inaccuracies, Colonel.
It's no wonder you're lost.
We're not lost.
Well, whatever it
is you have lost,
you'll not find
it with this map.
Camp Watson is not
south as it says here,
but it's directly east
through the high pines
for a day and a half until
you reach the Grass Valley.
And then it is south for
another two days along the fur
traders' path.
I drew that map, girl.
Well, then, you're not such
a great red paint tracker
after all.
Red: [laughs]
I reckon your
navigator should at least
know where you come from.
I'll be happy to replace
him as a part of your outfit
if your pay is up to snuff.
[laughter]
Now, if you'll
excuse me, Colonel, I
have to kill an animal
that is very dear to me.
And I don't need no one around.
It's a private matter.
Go on then.
[laughs]
Good Lord, that girl's got
a sass on her, don't she?
I'm growing fond of that sass.
[intriguing music]
♪ ♪
[distant banging]
[distant grunting]
[rhythmic pounding, grunting]
Ada: Get off of her!
[grunts] What the fuck?
Ma'am, are you OK?
What did he do--
I'm OK, Ada.
Calvin: What the fuck you
think you're doing, girl?
Ada: I could ask you
the same question, sir,
if I could even call you that.
You either join in or
you get the fuck out.
Join in what?
I said no!
Calvin: [grunts]
Ada: Ma'am, you
need to get warm.
You're sick.
Come with me.
[thud]
[grunts]
Never interrupt a man
in the middle of a screw.
Ada: [whimpering]
Calvin: [grunting] That
whore belongs to me!
[thudding]
[high-pitched ringing]
[distorted] [coughing]
Emily: [panting]
[door slams]
No, no. No!
Emily! Emily, come on, honey.
Come on, baby.
Please just let me in.
Emily, please.
Come on, honey.
It's just you and me now.
Come on, come on.
Fuck!
[tense music]
You, for making me
lose my interest.
[mumbling]
♪ ♪
Screw this, girl.
I don't give a fuck what Fiddler
said to keep our hands off you
and mind our business.
[slams]
♪ ♪
Ain't no one ever laid a
hand on me and kept the hand!
You sneaky bitch. [panting]
♪ ♪
[grunting]
[slamming]
Come on, come on.
Emily!
Emily, honey.
Come on, girl.
[pounding]
Come on, honey.
Let me in.
[door rattling]
[whispering] Why'd you
have to make trouble?
[pounding]
He's gonna kill us both now.
[pounding, tense music]
What are you doing?
[pounding]
Calvin: Ada!
Ada, it's just you and me here.
Where you gonna go?
[pounding]
Ada!
[door rattling]
[pounding]
[gunshot]
[gasps]
♪ ♪
All right, I'm coming in!
[women gasping]
Calvin: [grunting]
♪ ♪
[gun clicking]
[grunting]
♪ ♪
[gunshot]
Ah! [agonizing screams]
[door rattling]
[screaming continues]
[thud]
Ah, Fuck!
[gunshots ringing]
- [grunts]
[gasps]
[gunshot]
[screaming]
Fuck, God damn it.
Emily: [gasping]
[wood creaking]
[door creaking]
Calvin: [grunting]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
Fuck.
[mumbling]
[sobbing]
♪ ♪
[high-pitched ringing]
[thud]
♪ ♪
[birds chirping]
[horses clomping, approaching]
♪ ♪
John: You understand what
it is I'm asking you?
Emily: Yes, Fiddler.
John: I ain't asking you
about any of this shit later.
I'm asking you about
that night on the river.
Perry dragged you
out, didn't he?
I was lucky it
was shallow enough.
It was freezing cold.
Charlie came up soon after,
put bullets in Perry's mule.
I guess that's
what first he saw.
Perry took off and
Charlie pursued.
I went to the ground and, uh--
guess I don't
remember much after.
John: Hm.
Burial Perry snuck
off into the night.
Took us till first
light to find him.
That's why what I'm asking
you is so important.
Yes, Fiddler.
What did he say to you?
Emily: Not a word, Fiddler.
Did he have the
militia bag on him?
I think so?
He did or he
didn't have the bag?
Did. He did.
John: Good.
That is good.
That means the gold is
close by in these woods.
[chuckles]
Calvin: [screaming] Get off!
Charlie: Hold still.
Calvin: Oh, Charlie,
don't cut off my leg!
I won't!
Calvin: My leg!
[grunting] Fiddler!
Fiddler, please.
Tell Charlie you don't
need to take my leg off.
John: How is he?
Calvin: [sobbing]
We're gonna need to take off
just above the ankle at least.
Looks to be
mostly gone anyhow.
Calvin: Oh, god!
Oh, god, it's all mangled!
That filthy piece of shit bitch.
Fiddler-- Fiddler, you
gotta kill her for me
and bring the body in here
so I can see you have!
Please!
Charlie: Keep still.
Give me your rifle.
It's over there,
by the bucket.
[panting] Oh, fuck!
John: Your leg is gonna
come off or it's not.
Either way, you've got no
foot at the bottom of it.
[foreboding music]
You're of no use to me anymore.
♪ ♪
No, no.
The whore is
still lying to me.
I want to know why.
Calvin: Fiddler.
[screaming]
♪ ♪
How'd you get that
scar on your face?
Was in Lawrence.
Few years back, a couple of
jayhawkers raided my village
and took my daughter.
Put a ball in my temple.
I was laying in my own blood
for hours before I was found.
What happened
to your daughter?
You shouldn't
have shot our boy.
What regiment did you
say you're from again?
Meh.
You.
Come along.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
There she is.
[ominous music]
I believe this ghost has been
haunting your cabin, Ms. Horn.
What is the armory for?
John: I rounded up
these guns for my men.
Here's yours, Ada,
your Hawken Saint Louis
54 caliber, owned by Major
General Edward Horn, US
Army officer and
Pinkerton operative,
passed on to his
daughter and only kin.
We fixed it up for you.
I ain't seen a muzzle loader
like this in five years.
I applaud you for trying to
kill any sort of animal with it.
But it's a good thing you
never used it on a man.
Bullet would have
flown by him by a mile,
and you would have been left
helpless reloading the thing.
[chuckles]
I've never been
much with a firearm.
John: [chuckles]
Ada: Much to my father's dismay.
I cannot tell you,
Ada, that you have
put me in an easy situation.
There's trouble with my
men about what you done.
I figured.
John: Looking back, do
you think your actions may
have been drastic?
You were not there, sir.
John: She is a whore, Ada.
Do you know what that is?
She was rendering a service.
What I saw was of no service.
It was of a brutal
and rough nature.
And I will not tolerate
it in my outpost.
This is yours, Ada.
Now, this one, this is a slant
breech Sharps, 36-inch barrel,
longer than a carbine.
Feel it.
Take an aim at your hungry ghost
out there, through the sight.
Feel the weight of it?
More meanness to
it, more commitment.
This is a single shot,
but accurate as you need.
Bring it back to cock
and pull the trigger.
[gun clicking]
[gunshot]
If I'm truthful, Ada,
I can't say that I'm
too bothered about Calvin Ed.
He's an ill-mannered boy,
got a rudeness in him
that I don't take to.
Did you kill those soldiers?
What soldiers, Ada?
The ones whose
uniforms you're wearing.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
John: [chuckles]
[muffled gunshots]
[disembodied grunting]
[distant gunshot]
soldier: [grunts] Ow!
This one is for you, 2 pounds.
For me?
John: I won't stop you from
making the arduous and unwise
journey on to California.
But this outpost does suit
me, Ada, and you here with it.
[gunshot]
[chuckles]
For your hospitality, Ms. Horn.
Maybe one day you will grow
into a great outlaw yourself.
Thank you, sir.
Call me John.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
[footsteps crunching]
[ominous music]
[chimes tinkling]
[cloth swishing]
♪ ♪
[distorted laugh]
[hooves stomping]
♪ ♪
[laughter, chatter]
[cloth rustling]
[drawer clattering]
[footsteps]
Hey!
♪ ♪
[wind howling,
footsteps crunching]
♪ ♪
John: Not often in our
riding have we stumbled
upon a place such as this.
It is unusual.
John: Its proximity to the
Barlow Road and Union Dresses
makes it an extraordinary
hideout for us.
We're growing
restless here, John.
[chuckles] You grow
restless, Charlie.
I'm settling in nicely.
Emily: When are we
leaving this place?
Our caretaker is not much
more than a wild girl,
ill-raised, and dangerous
in her stupidity.
Last evening, I
was doing laundry
and I found these crumbled
up inside the girl's dresser.
Those hogs ain't
the only reason we
got wolf snapping at our heels.
Charlie: [chuckles]
Emily: Don't you
be snickering now.
Nobody's told this young
woman how to be a woman.
I'll bring her around.
John: Hold on, Charlie.
Go talk to young Ada.
Take as long as you need.
Thank you, Fiddler.
[tapping]
[fire crackling]
Washed those pants you soiled.
[distant hammering]
[door creaking]
Do you need more medicine?
You'd do best to just listen.
[distant hammering]
You have no idea what
these men are truly like.
I've ridden with
them since Tennessee
and I've seen things
that could only be
described as the devil's work.
They impart no war
except their own.
They took me from my
family and then killed
them all, even my baby sister.
Only way I survived
day to day is
by giving them what they want.
Now you have
something they want.
And we both know what that is.
[hammering]
Ah!
Shit!
[grunting] Damn.
You got the gold.
I'm the only one
who knows for sure.
But I can tell
they're stewing on it.
You got the wrong idea.
I lied for you.
I saw Perry before
they caught him.
He told me where he
buried that gold.
He trusted me.
I overheard Ten Charlie say
they found nothing there.
You don't have to
think too hard to guess
that you found the satchel and
are holding on to what's inside.
Ada: What made him trust you?
I'm a prisoner just like he was,
just like you are.
Sonofabitch. [huffing]
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
Oh.
[sighs]
♪ ♪
[chuckles]
Emily: You confess to
Fiddler what you've done,
he'll kill you.
You don't, he'll
kill you anyway,
maybe make it last longer.
I ain't afraid.
Emily: Those are words.
And I understand where
they're coming from.
But you ain't looked
in the face of it.
Then we will escape.
We would be hunted
down in less than a day.
So what's the plan?
- We kill 'em.
- What?
Emily: We kill 'em all tonight.
- You speak too fast.
- It must be a surprise.
We do it at dinner.
I couldn't.
Emily: I seen your Remington.
Make sure it's loaded.
Ada: That is two girls against
four cold-blooded killers.
[ominous music]
Who told you I'm
not cold-blooded?
[drawer rattling]
♪ ♪
John: [chuckles] Might
be time to give it up.
Give what up, sir?
That pen is a hospice
for dying swine.
It looks as if they
all have pneumonia now.
It's a sad day.
We'll help you carve them up.
Are you and your men riding
out soon or would you like stew?
You show Red
your new Remington?
No, sir.
Why don't you go get
it so he can have a look?
[chuckles]
[gun clicks]
Already loaded.
Let's have a
look here, Colonel.
[gun clicks]
John: You see the job
Red did with your door
after you fucked it all up?
Ada: I did.
Thank you for
undoing the damage.
Red: Mm-hmm.
Emily!
Emily: Yes, Fiddler?
Why don't you take
Red here to the bedroom,
show him the benefits
of a job well done.
Red: Sounds fine by me.
[laughs] The girl's
ready to go. [laughs]
John: Ada, come and sit with me.
Misery loves company.
And my men are all
otherwise engaged.
[paper rustling]
"Outpost will be abandoned
within the appropriate amount
of time, a day or two
at most, as conditions
have become too harsh."
So on and so forth.
"I'm also leaving
this logbook behind
as a marker that we were here."
[bed banging in distance]
When was it you wrote this?
[distant pounding]
Three nights ago.
John: After Perry
showed up then?
Before.
Calvin: [wailing]
I wish that boy would shut up.
[distant grunting, bed pounding]
Looks like this is
your only entry here.
Rest is your daddy's?
He said it was
for the Pinkertons.
John: [chuckles] I once seen
a Pinkerton hang from a noose
out on the border
near Minnesota.
He tore up and raped
this little Sioux girl,
not but nine years of age.
Ain't no saints, Adaline, just
as fucking evil as the rest.
I'll start the stew.
I say at least it was a girl,
not some little Sioux tadpole!
You never know!
That's why it's good
to keep the whore!
Got to keep your cock pointed
in the right direction.
[distant pounding, man grunting]
Prayer for the father.
[somber music]
A good man tried and true,
may he be warm and gentle,
and forgive the sins you do.
Prayer for the mother.
♪ ♪
His temperament has changed.
Red: Emily!
Get back in here.
They know.
[ominous music]
[laughter, chatter]
John: Take two bowls
and go care for Calvin.
Yes, Fiddler.
The whore has always
got a trick up her sleeve.
Always a surprise, I tell you.
I haven't found
that to be true.
You just don't know how to
get it out of her, Charlie,
like I do.
[door rattles]
Ada, come here beside me.
Surprised to see
the table already set
and my stew already served.
We were hungry.
Let us join hands
for the blessing.
Then we can chow down.
[ominous music]
Be with us, Lord, as we suffer
in sin, every man and woman
under your judgment.
We can only beg your mercy
as we await the punishments
you have in store.
We suffer equally and die.
No man can be
washed of his sins.
And no sin can be
left unpunished.
Amen.
men: Amen.
♪ ♪
Ada: [screaming]
John: Why would you
steal from me, Ada?
Ada: [screaming]
How did you think you
would get away with it?
Ada: [screaming]
Are you listening, girl?
[whimpering]
John: Let no sin go unpunished.
You are a thief and
a liar, a sinner.
I am the Lord's right hand!
[sobbing]
Charlie!
Yes, Fiddler?
Grab the shovel, get your horse.
Go dig up what is
rightfully mine.
Fiddler?
John: What's the
matter with you?
Don't you know
where she's hid it?
Ain't you figured it out?
It's been here the whole time!
Go take a look at her
poor mama's grave.
She ain't there,
though, is she, Ada?
Never was!
[glass breaking]
Died in childbirth in
San Fran-fucking-cisco--
very fucking clever!
[sobbing]
♪ ♪
Oh, damn.
Oh, sorry.
♪ ♪
Calvin: Ms. Emily?
[door rattles]
Ada: [screaming, sobbing]
Wait!
[thud]
You got no cause
to harm that girl
no matter what she done to you.
John: That so?
Emily: I've ridden with you long
enough to know what's coming.
But that girl ain't full
grown and don't understand.
There's no need for another
killing in this place.
John: Perry didn't have
no militia bag on him,
you bloodless harpy.
You lied to my face!
Make sure you're still
here when I return or I
will hunt you down for sport.
♪ ♪
[whimpering]
Fiddler!
[coins clinking]
At last.
[laughter]
John: We leave at first light.
Come on.
[ominous music]
I promised I'd pay my respect.
[laughs]
Don't you worry, Ada.
I'll make sure your
grave is unmarked,
just like your daddy's.
[screaming]
[thud]
♪ ♪
[high pitched
ringing, soft music]
♪ ♪
[fire crackling]
Are you awake, then?
You didn't kill me yet?
The whore begged
me to spare you.
[foreboding music]
She came screaming across
the mountain on horseback
just after I rendered
you unconscious.
Hey, give me that.
John: I was ready to kill you.
But she put on such
a theatrical display.
Emily: [gagging]
John: So I brought you back here
and turned it over in my mind,
trying to find the softness
for you I once felt.
♪ ♪
But it would be a
disservice to you, Ada,
if I spared you and left you
here disgraced and rotten,
festering like a sore
on this mountain,
a no-good, dog-shit
thief and liar.
Do it.
♪ ♪
Wouldn't be right to let you
go on with this diseased life.
[squelching]
Let's hear that union
prayer one more time.
Come on, out with it.
Red: Emily!
John: Deal not with us according
to our sins or misdeeds.
Emily, what you
put in this bottle?
Whoa!
That is not who God is.
Emily: That's for
all the evil you've
done to me, you son of a bitch.
[gunshot]
Ah!
[gunshots ringing]
[grunting]
[clattering]
[gunshot]
[drmatic music]
Shit.
[gunshot]
Red: Emily!
[ominous music]
[clattering]
Ah!
Bitch drugged me.
Shit.
Jesus, John.
John: Give me your gun.
The whore has got a rifle, shot
my fucking ear off, Charlie.
[foreboding music]
I'll take care of her.
Little girl is hiding
in the bedroom.
She's got the Hawken, so
she's only got one shot.
[footsteps crunching]
♪ ♪
[wolf howling]
[door creaking]
♪ ♪
[footsteps]
[footsteps, floor creaking]
♪ ♪
[slamming]
[leaves rustling]
♪ ♪
[gun clicking]
[wood rattles]
♪ ♪
[distant coughing]
[gunshots ringing]
[unsettling music]
♪ ♪
[door rattles]
[water splashing]
♪ ♪
[rattles]
[gunshot]
[thud]
Emily: Damn.
[coughing]
[ominous music]
[clears throat]
♪ ♪
[footsteps]
[clatters]
[tense music]
[gunshots ringing,
glass breaking]
♪ ♪
Poor Calvin's dead.
John: Then it is
an even contest.
Give me your Colt and rounds.
Is that all?
Red: That's all.
[bullet clinks]
[ominous music]
[creaking]
John: Ada.
[thud]
You can't run from me.
[creaking]
[distant footsteps]
♪ ♪
[gun clicking]
[gun clicks]
[gunshot]
[gun clicking]
Ah, hell.
[exhales]
[gunshot]
[grunts]
[chuckles]
♪ ♪
That's two pulls
from the repeater,
Ada, not too far away neither!
There's a strong chance
your girl didn't survive it,
not with Red at the trigger.
[rattles]
♪ ♪
[thud]
Just you and me now.
There's no more help coming.
[gun clicks]
[horse neighing,
quiet running steps]
[wolf howling]
[barking]
♪ ♪
[door rattling]
[gunshots ringing]
[tense music]
[panting]
♪ ♪
[gunshots ringing]
[thud]
[laughs]
[gun clicking]
- [grunts]
[gunshot]
- You-- [grunting]
[thud]
Ada: [whimpering] [grunting]
[somber music]
[grunting]
♪ ♪
[gun clicks]
John: [chuckles]
[chuckles]
- [whimpers]
- [chuckles]
Ada: [grunts]
[grunting]
[gunshot]
[tense music]
[grunting]
♪ ♪
[grunting, whimpering]
[gun clicks]
♪ ♪
[gunshot]
[grunts]
[panting, groaning]
[foreboding music]
[fire crackling, footsteps]
[gun clicks]
♪ ♪
Emily, my dear.
[gunshot, squelching]
[thud]
[somber music]
♪ ♪
[footsteps]
[rushed breathing]
Ada: [grunting]
[coughs] [gasping]
[wolf howling, pig squealing]
OK, we're gonna
have to move you.
You ready?
- [grunts]
- Come on.
- [screams]
OK, OK, OK, OK.
Hey, hey, hey.
The pain is something fierce.
But it's a false notion.
You ain't hurt bad.
Now, look at me.
We have to get you out of here.
[grunting, gasping]
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
[coins clattering]
[horse neighing]
[growling, barking]
[pig snorts]
[barking]
[grunting]
♪ ♪
[coins clattering]
[wolf growling]
♪ ♪
[gunshot]
[paws pounding]
[wolf barks]
[gun clicks]
♪ ♪
[gunshot]
[thud]
[grunting]
[wolf growling]
[coughing]
[wolf panting, ominous music]
[grunting]
♪ ♪
[gasping, grunting]
[gun clicks]
[wolf panting]
[short breaths]
[pensive music]
♪ ♪
[distant howling]
[somber music]
[chains clinking]
♪ ♪
Emily: Ada, I need
you to stay awake.
We've got a long ways to go.
I have to beat this.
Emily: That's why
you gotta stay awake.
Can you do that for me?
♪ ♪
Mine eyes have seen the glory
of the coming of the Lord.
Emily: Keep going, Ada!
He's trampling out the vintage
grapes of wrath are stored.
Emily: Hey, come on, we
got a long ways to go.
His truth is marching--
♪ ♪
on.
[soft melody]
♪ ♪
[Bryan Martin,
"Goin' for Broke"]
♪ ♪
♪ There's a train headed west ♪
♪ With a guitar and a chest ♪
♪ Full of songs that
ain't been sung ♪
♪ And there's a heart
that needs some rest ♪
♪ And a soul that's
done its best ♪
♪ To find where the leaving
goes before it's gone ♪
♪ Nah, I ain't
found no peace yet ♪
♪ Chasing that sunset ♪
♪ Looking for my piece of gold ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm tired of
watching y'all eat ♪
♪ I'mma get my seat
without losing my soul ♪
♪ I'm going for broke ♪
♪ Hush, hush, get some
sleep and close those eyes ♪
♪ No, don't you worry ♪
♪ Don't pay no mind ♪
♪ I'mma sneak right in
like a thief in the night ♪
♪ And only take what's owed ♪
♪ I'm going for broke ♪
♪ I'll trade these
tears in for dollars ♪
♪ I've been saving
them all this time ♪
♪ And this town will
run out of money ♪
♪ Long before I run out
of wrongs and rights ♪
♪ And I faced all my fears ♪
♪ I looked the
devil in his eyes ♪
♪ 'cause when you've
hit rock bottom ♪
♪ That's when you truly
learn how to fly ♪
♪ Now, I ain't
found no peace yet ♪
♪ Chasing that sunset ♪
♪ Looking for my piece of gold ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm tired of
watching y'all eat ♪
♪ I'mma get my seat
without losing my soul ♪
♪ I'm going for
broke, hush, hush ♪
♪ Get some sleep and
close those eyes ♪
♪ No, don't you worry ♪
♪ Don't pay no mind ♪
♪ I'mma sneak right in
like a thief in the night ♪
♪ And only take what's owed ♪
♪ I'm going for broke ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm going for broke ♪
♪ Nah, I ain't found no peace ♪
♪ Chasing that sunset ♪
♪ Looking for my piece of gold ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm tired of
watching y'all eat ♪
♪ I'mma get my seat
without losing my soul ♪
♪ I'm going for
broke, hush, hush ♪
♪ Get some sleep and
close those eyes ♪
♪ No, don't you worry ♪
♪ Don't pay no mind ♪
♪ I'mma sneak out of here
like a thief in the night ♪
♪ And only take what's owed ♪
♪ I'm going for broke ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm going for broke ♪